http://www.pennineteaandcoffee.co.uk/pages/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
Statement of intent Collection of personal information Storage of personal information Sharing information Cookies I.P. Address Access Links Security
You can choose whether to accept or decline Tracking Cookies when you first visit our web site, if you wish to change these settings please press the Privacy Settings button visible to the bottom right of this page.
Statement of intent
Our Privacy Policy explains how and why we collect personal information about you. We are committed to responsible management of personal information in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.
Collection of personal information
In order to receive certain information and to use certain services on this site you will be asked to provide personal information about yourself such as your name, address and email address. When you provide this information to us you consent to our use of that information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. This information will be used to provide you with the services that you have requested and to provide you with news and information about our products and services. If you no longer want to receive such information just let us know by email and we will stop sending it.
Storage of personal information
We will keep your personal information for as long as we need it to provide our products and/or services to you. We do not store credit card details nor do we share customer details with any 3rd parties. We will try to keep personal information which we hold about you up to date, but if you think that we are holding information which is inaccurate or you are otherwise unhappy about our use of your personal information then please send us an email to let us know.
Sharing information
We will not sell the personal information that we collect from you. We use the personal information which we collect from you to help us provide our products and/or services to you. Some data processing in relation to this site may be carried out for us by a third party and in some cases that may mean that the third party will receive your personal information. Such third provide guarantees to us that they will provide an adequate level of security. Any date processing carried out for us by a third party will be governed by a written contract between us and that third party, which contract will provide that the third party will only act on our instructions. Apart from this we will not share or transfer any personal information with any other third party unless we are required to do so by law.
Cookies
Some websites use cookies which are text only strings of information that the website you are visiting transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer. Their purpose is to identify users and to enhance the users experience by customising web pages. A cookie will usually contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, an expiry date for the cookie, and a value, which is usually a random generated unique number.
Types of cookies
Cookies may be either first party cookies or third party cookies. First party cookies are used by the website owner and third party cookies are used by a third party such as an advertiser or a web designer or a website host.
Cookies may be session cookies, which are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site or persistent cookies, which remain in the cookie file for much longer. How long persistent cookies remain in your browser depends on the duration given to the cookie.
Cookies may record personal data such as name, and email address and/or non-personal data such as IP address and unique but anonymous customer identity.
This site uses first party cookies to record on an anonymous basis
the precise time that you visit this site;
the precise web pages that you view;
the websites visited by you before and after you visit this site;
to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use this site to help us to improve the operation of this site and
items placed in the shopping basket
Please note that our cookies will not store your personal details. This site does not use third party cookies.
This site uses first party cookies to record
the precise time that you visit this site;
the precise web pages that you view and the websites visited by you before and after you visit this site;
to help us recognise you as a unique visitor when you return to this site and to allow us to tailor content for you
to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use this site to help us to improve the operation of this site;
to allow you to carry information across pages of our site an avoid having to re-enter information;
to allow you to maintain a shopping basket;
This site does not use third party cookies.
Refusing cookies
You are entitled to refuse the use of cookies on this site. However, search and shopping basket functionality will not work.
You can refuse cookies by making modifying the settings in your browser.
For more information about how to manage cookies visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org/
I.P. Address
This site logs your Internet Protocol (I.P.) address. All computers that are linked to the Internet have an I.P. number. An I.P. address does not provide identifiable personal information.
Access
You are entitled under the Data Protection Act 1998 to a copy of the personal information that we hold about you if you apply to us in writing. We may make a small charge for dealing with any such request.
Links
This site provides links to other websites. Our Privacy Policy applies only to this site and we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third party sites.
Security
This website processes online payments via our online store provider Shopify.co.uk All personal information is stored on their Secure Server, which uses SSL. We offer a range of easy payment methods including Pay Pal, Credit or Debit card payment live online via Shopify payment gateway - or you can be called back for your payment details if you prefer.
Rights of data subjects
We hereby inform you that, in accordance with Article 15 et seq. of the GDPR and under the conditions defined therein, you have the right to information about your personal data, as well as to rectification or deletion or restriction of the processing of your data, and you furthermore have a right to object to the processing and transfer of data.
You also have the right, under Article 77 of the GDPR, to lodge a complaint with a data protection regulatory authority if you believe that the processing of your personal data violated the GDPR. If the processing is based on Article 6 Para. 1 (a) of the GDPR or Article 9 Para. 2 (a) of the GDPR (consent), you also have the right to revoke your consent at any time without affecting the legality of the processing that took place up until your consent was revoked.
Right to information, Art. 15 GDPR You have the right to request information about whether and to what extent your personal data will beprocessed (in particular processing purpose, recipient of the data, duration of storage, etc.).
Right to rectification of data, Art. 16 GDPR You have the right to request correction of your stored data if it is incorrect or incomplete. This includes the right to be completed/corrected through supplementary statements or communications.
Right to deletion of data, Art. 17 GDPR You have the right to request the deletion of your personal data. This is possible, for example, if the data is no longer required for the purposes for which it was collected or if the data is to be deleted due to legal obligations. In individual cases, however, this right may be excluded.
Right to restriction of processing, Art. 18 GDPR You have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. This is possible, for example, if your data is incorrectly recorded or if the data processing is unlawful. If the processing is restricted, the data may be processed only in narrowly defined cases.
Right to data transferability, Art. 20 GDPR You have the right to demand that the data concerning you be returned to you or to a person appointed by you in a standard electronic, machine-readable data format, if you have provided this data yourself.
Right to object, Art. 21 GDPR You have the right, for reasons arising from your particular situation, to object to the processing of personal data concerning you at any time with future effect, provided that the processing of the data serves to protect legitimate interests (see Article 6 Para. 1 lit. e), f) of the GDPR). If you object, it will be verified whether the legal requirements for the processing of your data are in place and, if they are not in place, no further processing of your data will be undertaken.
Right to complain to the regulatory authorities, Art. 77 GDPR You have the right to contact the competent regulatory authority of the European Union or the member states at any time for possible violations of data protection regulations.
Newsletter
Our website offers you the opportunity to subscribe to our newsletter. The newsletter provides you periodically with information about our products, offers & services. To receive our newsletter, we require a valid email address. We will review the email address you provide for the purpose of determining whether you are in fact the owner of the email address provided or whether the actual owner of said address is authorized to receive the newsletter. When subscribing to our newsletter, we will store your IP address as well as the date and time you subscribed. This serves to protect us in the event a third party improperly and without your knowledge makes use of your email address to subscribe to our newsletter. We will not collect any other data. The data thereby collected is used solely for the purpose of receiving our newsletter. Use of MailChimp Newsletter Consent You will be asked to consent to the use of your personal data to receive our newsletter as follows: “I have read the privacy policy and I give my consent to data being processed by a service provider located in the United States”. We use the newsletter to provide you with regular updates about our offers. To receive our newsletter, you will need a valid email address. We will then check the email address entered to ensure that you are actually its owner or if its owner has agreed to receive our newsletter. By registering for the newsletter, we will save your IP address and date and time of registration. This will be used in case a third party misuses your email address to subscribe to our newsletter without your knowledge. We will not compare the data collected during newsletter registration with any other data that might be collected by other components of our site.
Newsletter by MailChimp
We use MailChimp to send our newsletter to our subscribers. MailChimp is a service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC, 512 Means Street, Suite 404, Atlanta, GA 30318, USA. The data stored when you registered for the newsletter (email address, name, IP address, and time and date of registration) will be sent to a server operated by The Rocket Science Group in the United States and stored there in accordance with its EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Further information about the data protection offered by MailChimp can be found at: http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/ You may cancel your newsletter subscription and revoke your consent to the storage of this data at any time with future effect. For instructions to take this step, please refer to the confirmation email and each newsletter. Newsletter tracking Our newsletter includes so-called web bugs that allow us to recognise if and when an email has been opened and which links in the email have been clicked by its recipient. This data is stored by us so that we can best align our newsletter to the wishes and interests of our subscribers. Accordingly, the data thus collected is used to send personalised newsletters to each recipient. You will be asked to consent to the use of your personal data as follows: “I agree that my data and my user responses will be stored electronically by newsletter tracking so that I can receive a personalised newsletter. The revocation of the consent to receive the newsletter constitutes a revocation of the consent for the tracking described above.” By revoking the consent to receive the newsletter, the consent to the aforementioned tracking is revoked.
http://www.visitorsdetails.com
Registered Fairtrade Distributor FFdistp0013 -www.fairtrade.org.uk
Company Registration Number 4743172
